#### PROFILE SUMMARY

## MONICAH WANJIRU

P.O Box 418-00902, Kikuyu Tel: +254 714 395 812

Email:monicahwanjiru205@gmail.com

Software developer with 1 year experience in software requirements analysis, design, development, and deployment of software solutions. Proven capability to build interactive, usercentric, reliable applications and their practical implications to a company. Among the skills I have successfully acquired include; Advanced knowledge in building systems in ReactJS, Redux, JavaScript, Typescriprt, HTML5, CSS3 bootstrap. I also possess the capacity to work in a team and engage their effort in order to achieve the set objectives. My focus is to secure a position where my skills and expertise will be utilized in contributing to the growth of the organization.

## **EDUCATION**

- Women Techsters Fellowship Web Development Certification; 2023-2024
- **FreeCodeCamp** Web Development Certification; 2023-2023
- **Udemy –**ReactJS; 2023- 2023
- Bachelor of Arts (Economics) University of Nairobi

### PROFESSIONAL COURSES

- Certificate in Statistical Packages University of Nairobi
- CPA Sec 1& 2-Vision institute of professional

## **KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES**

- **Programming Languages**: JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3
- Frameworks and Libraries: ReactJS, Redux, Bootstrap
- Tools and Platforms: Git, Visual Studio Code
- Other Skills: Data Analysis, Problem-Solving, Team Collaboration

## **WORK HISTORY**

#### Freelance

Software Developer Oct 2023 to Sept 2024

- Developed dynamic web applications using JavaScript and ReactJS.
- Collaborated on web application projects at the Women Techsters Fellowship Bootcamp.

- Fixed bugs and optimized performance for React-based applications.
- Contributed to the design and implementation of user-friendly features for various projects.

## **Accounts Intern**

## **Integrated Design Studios Limited**

Sept 2021 – April 2022

- Managed daily transactions and reconciled banking transactions.
- Maintained and updated inventory and general ledger records.
- Processed communications and coordinated with clients.

### **PROJECTS**

### **Interactive E-commerce Website**

• Built a responsive e-commerce platform using ReactJS, integrating Redux for state management.

## **Portfolio Website**

• Designed and developed a personal portfolio website using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to showcase skills and projects.

# **Gen-Z Dictionary**

• Developed a dynamic and interactive dictionary application using JavaScript, aimed at decoding modern slang and phrases.

## **REFEREES**

### Harrison Kimani,

Backend Developer, Yousician

Tel: +254719619017

Email: hrrsnkimani103@gmail.com

Jonas Rotich,

Monitoring, Evaluation and Learning Officer,

**RIDA** 

Tel: +254 723684456

Email: rotichjonah4@gmail.com

## Winnie Mburu

Manager Empso

Sacco

Tel: +254 710578098

Email: winnieshikuh@gmail.com